### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Simplicity, creativity, and passion have always stood out to me as signs of greatness, and I strive to infuse these traits into everything that I create. I bring unique life experience, communication skills, and a deep love for problem solving to every project. I want to work for awesome companies and create incredible things, so if that is something you are interested in, I would love the opportunity to work with you.

# **SKILLS**

01 Computer			02 Knowledge		
	Ruby	Javascript	Team Dynamics	REST Conventions	
	Rails	Bootstrap	Rapid Learning Skills	Interface Design	
	AngularJS	Ember.js	OO Design Patterns	Test Driven Development	
	HTML & CSS	SQL	Agile Web Development	Pair Programming	

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Ruby Developer | OpenArc, Pittsburgh PA | June 2015 to present

- > Develop consumer based features and applications using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Ember.js, HTML, CSS and pair based programming.
- > Collaborate with Product Management and User Experience experts regarding product definition, schedule, scope and project-related decisions

Web Developer | Turing Group, Evanston IL | January 2015 to June 2015

- > Work along with a team following Agile methodologies to develop single page web application built on AngularJS, Rails, Bootstrap and SQL Server.
- > Collaborate on smaller projects utilizing new technologies and creative problem solving

Web Development Student | Dev Bootcamp, Chicago | September to Decemeber 2014

- > 19 week intensive training in Ruby, Rails, HTML 5/CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, Git and Heroku
- > Led team in developing a final project over an 8 day time frame utilizing team dynamics, version control, database design, and maintaining a production environment

## **EDUCATION**

Web Developer Training August to December 2014 Dev Bootcamp, Chicago

Master of Music 2009 to 2011 University of Illinois, Champaign-Urbana

Bachelor of Music 2004 to 2009 University of Mississippi

## LANGUAGE SKILLS





